So in the last lecture I explained Ted reactor's all about components and that components are awesome.
Bu yzden son derste Ted Reaktr'nn tm bileenleri ve bileenlerin harika olduunu akladm.
That's actually Cedar's on a real web page here's react.
Aslnda Cedar'n gerek bir web sayfasnda olmas burada tepki verir.
J.S. dot org which is the official web page.
J. S. resmi web sayfas olan dot org.
Or do you react to them.
Veya onlara tepki verir misiniz?
And if we have a look at it it is actually built with re-act of course.
Ve ona bir gz atarsak, aslnda tabii ki yeniden hareketle ina edilir.
This looks like a normal web page and it is of course but we can split this up into components.
Bu normal bir web sayfasna benziyor ve tabii ki bu, ancak bunlar bileenlere ayrabiliriz.
We've got this hattery component in there we get these single navigation item components.
Bu hattery bileenini orada buldk, bu tek navigasyon esi bileenlerini elde ettik.
We got this starting image call to action components here and we got all our elements here down here
de DS ekster kod parac bileenleri ylnn solunda baz aklamalar olan yllar gibi daha fazla bileen gryoruz.
where they advertise react and what it is about we see more components year like DS emerge code snippet
Bu balang grnts ars eylem bileenlerini burada aldk ve tm elerimize burada tepki verdiklerini duyurduk ve
components year with some descriptions to the left of it.
burada ne olduunu gryoruz, bunun nedeni
All these things are basically building blocks which we can of course easily consider as reusable pieces
Btn bunlar temel olarak yap talar olup elbette kolayca yeniden paralar olarak dnebiliriz
and actually are reusing this aliments year.
ve aslnda bu aliments yln tekrar kullanyoruz.
We got one element here and then the same element with different content being used below it.
Burada bir e var ve daha sonra, altnda kullanlan farkl ierikli ayn e.
Now of course you can hard code all that with just H-G mail javascript and C-s else but then you will
imdi elbette tm bunlar sadece H-G mail javascript ve C-s else ile kodlayabilirsiniz, ancak
have to repeat your code over and over again here with components you build your own h m l elements
kodunuzu tekrar tekrar burada, kendi h m l elerinizi oluturduunuz bileenlerle tekrar etmeniz gerekecek
so to say and then you just reuse that element.
ve bylece o eleman tekrar kullanyorsunuz demektir.
And behind the scenes does H Tim L element has all this content already inside of it and we'll see this
Ve perde arkasnda H Tim L eleman tm ierii iine alm durumda ve bunu
in detail in a second.
bir saniyede ayrntl olarak greceiz.
And that's a good example would be you would have me here on the page where I searched for the UK as
Ve bu bana iyi bir rnek, beni burada tepki verme alternatifi olarak ngiltere'yi
an alternative to react.
aradm sayfada bulursun olurdu.
There we see we get a lot of components too.
Orada ok fazla bileen aldk gryoruz.
We got that whole hador with the search bar component.
Arama ubuu bileeni ile btn bu hadoriz var.
Then we got the search result summary component here where it also allows us to filter the search results
Ardndan, arama sonu zet bileeni burada, arama sonularn ve daha sonra arama sonularn
and then the search results themselves.
kendimiz szp filtrelememize izin veriyor.
We got really used list item components here.
Burada gerekten kullanlan liste esi bileenleri var.
Each of them has an image and a different title.
Her biri bir imaja ve farkl bir unvere sahiptir.
But in the core they all are the same.
Ancak znde hepsi ayndr.
They all have the same structure.
Hepsinin yaps ayndr.
And you do me also uses a javascript framework to achieve this and to have an easier time developing.
Ve bunu yapmak iin ayrca bir javascript erevesi kullanyorum ve daha kolay bir gelime zaman var.
And that's important.
Ve bu nemli.
Maintaining and updating this page.
Bu sayfay gncelleme ve gncelleme.
So does why components are awesome and why we as a developer probably want to use components and that
gelitirici olarak muhtemelen bileenleri kullanmak istiyoruz; bu nedenle de tm bileenleri ilgilendiriyor.
is why we act is all about components.
yleyse, bileenlerin mthi ve neden bir